<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<campus>
	<building name="greystone">
		<id>greystone</id>
		<name>Greystone</name>
		<date>1865</date>
		<desc>Office of the current College President</desc>
		<info>
			The Rosenlund Carriage House, currently called Greystone is situated in the center of campus between Rt. 9 and the Hudson River. The Greystone building displays outstanding features of the Gothic Revival style. These features, combined with the historic landscape features of lawns, paths, treed areas, and drives exemplifies estate dependencies with related landscape from the mid-nineteenth century. This significant building and associated ground in this nominated district retain a high degree of integrity of style and site from the early estate.
		</info>
		<info>
			A. J. Downing's The Architecture of Country Houses were employed at the carriage house. Downing states that the most efficient way to combine a barn and a stable/carriage house was to place the building in an area where the ground slopes to create a separate barn level at grade on one side of the building and a stable/carriage house at the higher grade on the other side of the building. The lower level was to be utilized as a root cellar and a barn for cows while the middle level or first floor was used to house horses and wagons. Hay and grain would be stored above the wagon area. Such a floor plan was designed for the early carriage house. When the Marist Brothers first occupied the site and the carriage house had wagon storage at the east end of the main floor and horse stalls at the west end; the access was through the north facade. The upper level was the hay loft and a blacksmith's shop occupied part of the cellar.
		</info>
		<info>
			The aesthetic concerns expressed in Downing's book encompassed the use of construction material, decorative trims, roof styles and lines and varied floor plans. He favored stone in a dark color to achieve the stateliness required for estate buildings, yet roughly dressing the stone and laying it randomly would enhance its picturesque qualities. A. J. Downing believed the graceful lines of flared eaves echoed the gentle sloping hillsides of a riverside property and that such a treatment was appropriate for a roof's edge. Asymmetrical buildings were considered more artistic and visually striking when combined with broad window trims used to accentuate the feature and merge with other involved in the design of these estate dependencies, clear evidence of his principles and the employment of his techniques can be found at the Rosenlund carriage house.
		</info>
		<info>
			Since the construction of the carriage house in 1865, there have been three remodeling's starting in 1909, then 1928, and finally 1964. Major renovations were made to Greystone in 1928 for laboratories and a library. A third story was added for more dorm space, together with windows and the tower and stairs. The wooden floors were replaced by concrete floors supported by steel beams. Brother Paul Acyndinus did the electrical wiring. Cost of the construction was $30,000. Cost of the furnishings was $10,000. The steam laundry that was installed in 1909 was transferred to Marian in 1928 as well. Throughout the years Greystone has served as a dormitory, classrooms, science labs, and a library. Since 1964, Greystone has been the President's building, where the College President's office resides along with the academic dean's office. The Marist Brothers named the building "Greystone" because of its distinctive stonewalls.
		</info>
		<images>21</images>
	</building>
	
	<building name="kieran">
		<id>kieran</id>
		<name>Kieran Gatehouse</name>
		<date>1865</date>
		<desc>Office space; Private residence</desc>
		<info>
			Listed on the state and national Registers of Historic Places, the Kieran Gatehouse dates to 1865 and was a gatehouse on the estate purchased by the Marist Brothers in 1908. This quaint cottage has remained in constant use, first as a headquarters for the Poughkeepsie Province of the Marist Brothers and then as office space and a private residence. Brother Paul Ambrose Fontaine used the Gatehouse as his office during his tenure as President of the College. The Gatehouse was renamed the Kieran Gatehouse in October 1990 when it was dedicated to the late Brother Kieran Thomas Brennan. Not only was Brother Brennan a long-time trustee of Marist College, but he was also the director of student Brothers from 1954 to 1964.
		</info>
		<images>6</images>
	</building>

	<building name="stpeters">
		<id>stpeters</id>
		<name>St. Peter's</name>
		<date>1865</date>
		<desc>Residence for administrative offices</desc>
		<info>
			Built circa 1865, St. Peter's originally housed the Rosenlund Estate's gardener and his family. The Marist Brothers purchased the estate in 1908 and until 1969, St. Peter's served as a residence for the Marist Brothers. Currently it houses administrative offices. It is named St. Peter's because the Brothers who lived there from 1909 until 1936 taught in St. Peter's school in Poughkeepsie.
		</info>
		<info>
			Later, as the number of Brothers attached to the Scholasticate (the post High School) grew, St. Peter's was used to house some of the faculty. An addition was put on the front of the building toward the road passing in front of it. This addition was used as an office for Brother Nilus Donnelly, who was constructing new buildings on the property. Another addition was built on the side of St. Peter's facing Route 9. This part of the building housed faculty of Marist College as well as the printer Brother Tarcisius and Gardeners Brother Abelus and Brother Sanctus. It also housed the print shop, which was used to print documents for the Marist Brothers Province as well as the College. These additions were demolished in 1969, when the print shop was moved to the gym and the faculty was moved to Benoit House and the facade of the original building was restored to its former design.
		</info>
		<info>
			St. Peter's currently houses the staff of the Upward Bound program. Founded in the spring of 1965, Marist College's program is among the longest established in the country. It has helped motivate and academically prepare hundreds of disadvantaged high school students from the Hudson Valley to pursue a college education. Upward Bound is an outstanding example of Marist's longstanding commitment to serve the community beyond the campus.
		</info>
		<images>8</images>
	</building>

	<building name="greenhouse">
		<id>greenhouse</id>
		<name>Greenhouse</name>
		<date></date>
		<desc></desc>
		<info></info>
		<images></images>
	</building>

	<building name="farm">
		<id>farm</id>
		<name>Farm</name>
		<date></date>
		<desc></desc>
		<info></info>
		<images></images>
	</building>

	<building name="cemetery">
		<id>cemetery</id>
		<name>Cemetery</name>
		<date></date>
		<desc></desc>
		<info></info>
		<images></images>
	</building>

	<building name="macpherson">
		<id>macpherson</id>
		<name>MacPherson</name>
		<date></date>
		<desc></desc>
		<info></info>
		<images></images>
	</building>

	<building name="marian">
		<id>marian</id>
		<name>Marian Hall</name>
		<date>1948</date>
		<desc>Underclassman residence</desc>
		<info>
			The present Marian building was built as a gymnasium in 1948. It was the first large building to be constructed by the Marist Brothers on what is now the current Marist College campus. Marian was used primarily as a gym with other facilities constructed in the wings. Some of these facilities included a carpenter shop, a printing shop, a laundry room, garages, and storage space. In 1983 Marian Hall was transformed into a dormitory. The wings were renovated in order to make a second floor. The current Marian Hall stands next to the historic Greystone building and currently houses around 100 first and second year students.
		</info>
		<images>12</images>
	</building>

	<building name="cannery">
		<id>cannery</id>
		<name>Cannery</name>
		<date></date>
		<desc></desc>
		<info></info>
		<images></images>
	</building>

	<building name="stmarys">
		<id>stmarys</id>
		<name>St. Marys</name>
		<date></date>
		<desc></desc>
		<info></info>
		<images></images>
	</building>
	
	<building name="novitiate">
		<id>novitiate</id>
		<name>Novitiate</name>
		<date></date>
		<desc></desc>
		<info></info>
		<images></images>
	</building>

	<building name="studyarea">
		<id>studyarea</id>
		<name>Study Area</name>
		<date></date>
		<desc></desc>
		<info></info>
		<images></images>
	</building>


	<building name="chapel">
		<id>chapel</id>
		<name>Our Lady Seat of Wisdom Chapel</name>
		<date>1953</date>
		<desc>Chapel owned by Marist College</desc>
		<info>
			Our Lady Seat of Wisdom Chapel is the crown jewel in the diadem of buildings which comprise the Marist College campus. The chapel was built in 1953 by Marist Brothers under the direction of Brother Nilus Donnelly. Its circular design was one of the first for a Catholic church in the United States. The design was later established with the Second Vatican Council in 1965 in which churches began to move their altars into a similar circular shape.
		</info>
		<info>
			Brother Nilus decided that instead of stained glass windows he would line the perimeter of the chapel with the photographic images of the Virgin Mary with accompanying quotes from the scripture. The images would be placed on heavy plastic and suspended on springs which compensated for the expansion from the sunlight and the contraction during the night. Rita Hunt, a professional model, and her husband were friends with Brother Nilus and volunteered to depict the Virgin Mary. Unfortunately, the images have faded due to the bleaching of the sun.
		</info>
		<info>
			Our Lady Seat of Wisdom Chapel forms the core, the anchor, and the inspiration for the Marist College campus.
		</info>
		<images>74</images>
	</building>

	<building name="adrian">
		<id>adrian</id>
		<name>Adrian Hall</name>
		<date>1957</date>
		<desc>Underclassman residence</desc>
		<info>
			Completed in 1957, Adrian Hall was among the first buildings constructed by the Marist Brothers. It was named in honor of Brother Adrian August, who was a well-known Music Master and Chemistry professor, who also served as long-time Master of Scholastics. The architectural design was created by Brother Nilus Vincent. He incorporated horizontal lines into the design to align with nature, as he believed the building was not only for space, but a shelter for the spirit of man.
		</info>
		<info>
			The estimated cost to build Adrian was $75,100, but was built for only $30,000. Originally, Adrian was meant to accommodate resident students and their parents, and to become a place where they could greet visitors on Sundays. The building first contained a sitting room and entertainment center, but later became the home of the Alumni Office and Marist Poll. It was also used as the advancement office, where people discussed topics regarding donations. Students used Adrian as a common space to hang out, eat, and study.
		</info>
		<info>
			In 2000, Adrian Hall was demolished to make way for the construction of the James A. Cannavino Library.
		</info>
		<images>20</images>
	</building>

	<building name="leo">
		<id>leo</id>
		<name>Leo Hall</name>
		<date>1963</date>
		<desc>Freshman residence</desc>
		<info>
			With its construction funded by a federal government loan, Leo Hall opened in 1963 as a dorm for Marist students. Six stories tall, it houses approximately 290 students and provides a lounge, recreation hall, and balconies for studying and relaxing. Resident students used to call it "Leo Hilton" because the dorm was able to satisfy their intellectual, recreational, and general needs and its location provided residents with beautiful views of the Hudson River. Women took up residence on the sixth floor when they were allowed to attend Marist in 1969. At one point, the basement of Leo was used as an alternative classroom because of the large increase in admitted students.
		</info>
		<info>
			Leo Hall is dedicated in memory of Brother Leo Brouiletter, who served as Provincial of the Marist Brothers from 1921 to 1930. In 1929 he secured the original charter for the Marist Normal Training School.
		</info>
		<info>
			Leo presently serves as a co-ed dorm for freshmen students at Marist.
		</info>
		<images>12</images>
	</building>

	<building name="sheahan">
		<id>sheahan</id>
		<name>Sheahan Hall</name>
		<date>1969</date>
		<desc>Freshman residence</desc>
		<info>
			In March of 1961 Brother Linus Richard Foy, President of Marist College, received confirmation for a government loan for a dormitory that would accommodate 120 students and three faculty advisors. This was the first building on the property that was not constructed by the Marist Brothers since the property was purchased in 1908. Sheahan Hall was one of the first dormitories where women lived when the College became a coeducational institution in 1969. It currently houses freshman students and is named in memory of Monsignor J. F. Sheahan, pastor of St. Peter's Church in Poughkeepsie. Monsignor Sheahan used his influence to help the Brothers purchase the Bech Estate in 1908. Today this property forms the entire Marist College campus south of the Waterworks Road (the main entrance to the campus).
		</info>
		<images>9</images>
	</building>

	<building name="donnelly">
		<id>donnelly</id>
		<name>Donnelly Hall</name>
		<date>1962</date>
		<desc>Academic building; Administrative offices</desc>
		<info>
			Donnelly Hall is named after Brother Nilus Donnelly, a physics professor at the time, who impacted the development of Marist College both physically and academically. Donnelly Hall was finally finished in 1962 after three long summers of hard work by schoolteachers who were untrained in construction work. Some obstacles the dedicated Marist Brothers overcame was the discovery of water seepage from an underground stream into the foundation holes. The water had to be pumped out and directed away from the worksite. Brother Nilus directed all the work and operated the heavy machinery.
		</info>
		<info>
			Donnelly Hall has served as headquarters for almost every college activity on campus in addition to academics and even a residence hall for lay students even though it was originally built to hold dorm rooms, cafeteria, bookstore, lecture halls, classrooms, and a library. Donnelly is currently home to the School of Science, science labs, the Fashion Program, photography darkrooms, lecture halls, classrooms, Security, Registrar, Financial Aid, Information Technology, Human Resources, the computer store, the Copy Center, and even a coffee shop.
		</info>
		<images>102</images>
	</building>

	<building name="mccann">
		<id>mccann</id>
		<name>James J. McCann Recreational Center</name>
		<date>1977</date>
		<desc>Athletic complex</desc>
		<info>
			The McCann Center is home to Marist College's intercollegiate, intramural, and recreational athletics programs. The original 57,200 square-foot McCann Center, including a field house, Olympic swimming pool, dance studio, and weight room, was built in 1977 with funding from the James J. McCann Foundation. The McCann Foundation again gave its support to construct a 20,000 square-foot addition that opened in 1997. The expansion features an 11,000 square-foot multipurpose gymnasium, a 4,300 square-foot weight training area, a 4,000 square-foot cardiovascular area, a student lounge and locker rooms, and the electronic Pepsi Athletic Hall of Fame, a multimedia room and computer lab honoring athletes and teams from Marist College and surrounding Dutchess County.
		</info>
		<info>
			The McCann Center was named after James J. McCann, who was born in Poughkeepsie in 1880. He and his family operated the McCann Feed and Grain Store on Main Street, and McCann eventually amassed a large estate through the stock market. In 1967, two years before his death, McCann established the McCann Foundation, which began awarding money in 1969 for "progressive human welfare work."
		</info>
		<images>11</images>
	</building>

	<building name="champagnat">
		<id>champagnat</id>
		<name>Champagnat Hall</name>
		<date>1964</date>
		<desc>Freshman residence</desc>
		<info>
			Champagnat, Marist's tallest building, was constructed in 1964 with a loan from the New York State Dormitory Authority. This nine-story building houses over 400 freshmen students and is connected to the Student Center by means of a breezeway.
		</info>
		<info>
			The building served two purposes when it was first built. It was not only a place where students could reside, but it became a student union as well. Together, these two facilities became known as Champagnat Hall. The goal of Champagnat was to bring students together to form new relationships and rekindle the spirit of the student body, taking Marist from a class-centered environment to a school-centered community.
		</info>
		<info>
			The complex boasted a fireplace lounge where students could hang out and relax. It also had a periodical library, study room, and lecture hall. The most impressive addition was the auditorium, which could serve as a lecture hall and provide a venue for the performing arts. It was an intimate theatre with a seating capacity of 358 persons and was the most well equipped theater between New York City and Albany.
		</info>
		<info>
			In the basement of the three-story student union lived Rathskeller, an on-campus bar and popular hangout for those legally able to drink, as well as a snack bar and party room. The ground floor contained the cafeteria with panoramic views of the Hudson River. A card room, T.V. lounge, game room, and photo lab were also located there.
		</info>
		<info>
			Eventually Champagnat and the student union became two separate identities. Champagnat would remain a dorm and the student lounges and campus services would now be housed in a Campus Center, later known as the Student Center.
		</info>
		<info>
			Champagnat is named after the French priest, Marcellin Champagnat, who founded the Marist Brothers in 1817. According to history, Champagnat encountered a dying boy on a mountainside who did not know of the existence of God. Haunted by the thought, this chance encounter motivated him to assume the responsibility of educating the young who would become the future leaders of the Church.
		</info>
		<images>15</images>
	</building>

	<building name="studentcenter">
		<id>studentcenter</id>
		<name>Student Center</name>
		<date>1965</date>
		<desc>Student recreation center</desc>
		<info>
			The Student Center is the most recognized building on the Marist campus. It brings the Marist community together in one central space for activities, dining, and the chance to form new relationships.
		</info>
		<info>
			The Campus Center was completed in 1965, with 66,000 square feet comprising of the Browsing Library, Gallery Lounge, and Fireside Lounge. It was originally a part of Champagnat Hall, but the building eventually separated into two distinct facilities.
		</info>
		<info>
			Plans for the new Student Center were included in the college's "Vision '94" campaign, which was completed in 1995. This $27 million campaign sought to renovate the old Campus Center by adding new facilities and updating those already existing. Funding for this project came from the sale of construction bonds through the New York State Dormitory Authority. Additional funds were provided by tuition, fees, and the release of the Canterbury apartments Marist students used in the past.
		</info>
		<info>
			As one of the largest construction jobs in Marist history, this campaign created the Rotunda, Cabaret, and Mid-Rise, adding an additional 63,000 square feet to the building. Renovations were made to the bookstore, dining facilities, performing arts center, and the campus green. A breezeway was installed between Champagnat and the Student Center to connect the two buildings. New offices and club rooms were created for the Student Government Association, The Circle, Health Services, and Student Activities. Three alcoves were installed for students as a place for meeting up and studying between classes. A new dining facility, the Cabaret, was constructed with a large area for performances, lectures, special events, and student activities. An adjoining Commuter Lounge became a place for off-campus students to do homework or relax with friends.
		</info>
		<info>
			Presently, the Student Center is, once again, under major construction to attach a multipurpose academic building. Renovations are being made to enhance the building for everyone. Specifically, improvements are being made to the Performing Arts Room, Student Government Association Office, and Nelly Goletti Theatre. A new music wing is being constructed to house the Marist Band, Singers, and Orchestra and will include rehearsal halls, practice rooms, music labs, classrooms, and faculty offices.  The dining hall will be completely transformed into a grander space with vaulted ceilings and increased seating capacity.  Efforts are being made to make the new building more environmentally friendly by making improvements to heating, ventilation, and air conditioning.
		</info>
		<images>35</images>
	</building>

	<building name="dyson">
		<id>dyson</id>
		<name>Dyson Center</name>
		<date>1990</date>
		<desc>Academic building</desc>
		<info>
			Dyson Center, completed in August of 1990, houses the School of Management and the School of Social &amp; Behavioral Sciences. It is named after Charles H. Dyson, a well-known businessman and philanthropist, and his late wife, Margaret. The building was Charles Dyson's 80th birthday present from his daughter and son.
		</info>
		<info>
			The three-story 53,000 square foot building contains 23 classrooms and 68 faculty offices, as well as seminar rooms and a computer lab. The Office of Graduate and Continuing Education, the Bureau of Economic Research, and corporate educational training programs are also located here. Students enjoy Dyson's coffee shop, where they can grab a quick bite to eat between classes, or stay awhile and study.
		</info>
		<info>
			The Dyson Center was built to fulfill the Marist's growing need for technology and space caused by renovations being made to Donnelly. The number of offices, classrooms, and seminar areas not only provided the students and faculty with adequate learning space, but with a prominent and technologically-advanced facility. It also served as the missing link connecting the North End with the center of campus, creating a more unified community.
		</info>
		<images>11</images>
	</building>

	<building name="lowell">
		<id>lowell</id>
		<name>Lowell Thomas Communications Center</name>
		<date>1987</date>
		<desc>Academic building</desc>
		<info>
			Construction for the Lowell Thomas Communication Center began in 1984 with generous gifts from generous donors. Robert R. Dyson, member of the college's board of trustees, became the project's first major donor with a gift of $250,000. The McCann Foundation donated a million dollars and Lowell Thomas Jr. made two individual gifts totaling $550,000. After three years of construction the building finally opened in 1987.
		</info>
		<info>
			The Lowell Thomas Communications Center provided accommodations for the academic schools of Communications and Computer Science &amp; Mathematics. (The School of Computer Science &amp; Mathematics would eventually move to its new home in Hancock in 2011). The building featured two television studios, film processing areas, two radio broadcast rooms, classrooms, and the Charles and Cornelia Murray Journalism Room, which contained anything a student would need to write, edit and present printed news. The first floor contained a display room which highlighted Lowell Thomas's exciting career as a famed newscaster, author, and world traveler.
		</info>
		<info>
			Renovations in 2012 have eclipsed the basement and first floor, giving way to a newly designed Digital Toolbox lab, sports communication center, and internship office.  Admissions and the Global Studies Department have also found a new home in Lowell Thomas. The newly-renovated basement houses the WMAR radio studio, the MCTV office, classrooms, a lounge area, and a screening room, complete with state-of-the-art equipment.
		</info>
		<info>
			Renovations to the second floor, which include updating the television equipment and studios, are scheduled to take place in the near future.
		</info>
		<images>13</images>
	</building>

	<building name="longview">
		<id>longview</id>
		<name>Longview Park</name>
		<date></date>
		<desc></desc>
		<info></info>
		<images></images>
	</building>

	<building name="newtownhouses">
		<id>newtownhouses</id>
		<name>New Townhouses</name>
		<date>1993</date>
		<desc>Upperclassman residence</desc>
		<info>
			The New Townhouses were built in 1993 and accommodate 144 junior and senior students in six buildings overlooking the Hudson River. Each building has a number of units with space for eight students, including living, dining, and lounging areas. The complex has its own central laundry facility. Some units are available to accommodate qualified, physical handicapped students.
		</info>
		<images>6</images>
	</building>

	<building name="byrne">
		<id>byrne</id>
		<name>Byrne House</name>
		<date>1963</date>
		<desc>Residence of the Counseling Center</desc>
		<info>
			The Byrne House was built during the expansion of Marist College in 1963 to house the Dominicas Fathers who were, at that time, college chaplains. After fulfilling its use, and a few renovations later, in 1985 the house became the new location of the Counseling Center and Health Services to serve as a Personal Development Center. Combining these services allowed students to come together in one space, making it more convenient and worthwhile to visit.
		</info>
		<info>
			More recently, Health Services moved back into the Student Center and Byrne has been established as the school ministry and permanent residence of the Counseling Center.
		</info>
		<info>
			The house was named after Brother George Francis Byrne. Originally from Western, New York, Brother Byrne came to Marist in 1949 to teach History. He became a Marist Brother on July 26, 1926 and served until his death on October 25, 1953. He was buried in the Marist Brother's cemetery.
		</info>
		<images>8</images>
	</building>

	<building name="fontaineannex">
		<id>fontaineannex</id>
		<name>Fontaine Annex</name>
		<date></date>
		<desc>Academic building</desc>
		<info></info>
		<images></images>
	</building>

	<building name="steelplant">
		<id>steelplant</id>
		<name>Steel Plant Studios</name>
		<date>1997</date>
		<desc>Art gallery; Studio</desc>
		<info>
			Marist purchased an industrial site across the street from Marist in 1997 to house the college library while the James A. Cannavino Library was being built.  After the Library was completed, Marist renovated the old storehouse and turned it into the Steel Plant Studios, a 3,200 square-foot space that is now home to the Marist College Art Gallery. Several kinds of studios live inside including 2-D/Graphic Design, Drawing &amp; Painting, 3-D Sculpture, Digital Media, and a studio specifically for Special Processes &amp; Techniques. It also features a 2,500 square-foot Art Gallery where students can display their work for members of the community to see. The Gallery holds its industrial-like feel with its concrete floors and 15-foot exposed ceilings. The Gallery is open from September to May and showcases the work of student and faculty artists working with various types of fine arts media.
		</info>
		<images>6</images>
	</building>

	<building name="stanns">
		<id>stanns</id>
		<name>St. Ann's Hermitage</name>
		<date>1997</date>
		<desc>Private residence</desc>
		<info>
			In 1905, with the help of Father H. Havens Richards, SJ, St. Ann's Hermitage was the first building in Poughkeepsie purchased by the Marist Brothers. It had previously been the homestead of the MacPherson family. Brother Zepheriny, FMS, purchased this estate from its owner, Mrs. Goodwin of New York City. The property, which was at the time a mile outside of the City of Poughkeepsie, included some 35 acres north of the Waterworks Road and sold for $9,000.00. This building was used as a Provincial House until the early fifties. In addition to the provincial administration, it also housed the Scholastics usually numbering around 75 students. There was a chapel with a pipe organ where a Jesuit from St. Andrew's celebrated daily mass. Also living in this building was a community consisting of the provincial tailors who made the cassocks for all the Brothers of the province. Others living in this building included a director, a cook, several young brothers to help in the tailor shop, in the garden, and with the laundry, a farmer who took care of the cows and pigs, and two farmers who took care of an extensive vegetable garden and a greenhouse which was located across from St. Peter's. The infirmary, which had from 5 to 13 Brothers who needed medical attention, was also located in this building.
		</info>
		<info>
			Between 1955 to 1957 the original Fontaine Hall was built to house the scholastics, the faculty was moved to St. Peter's, and the infirmary was relocated to Tyngsboro, Massachusetts. The farmers were moved to St. Peter's leaving the Hermitage empty. In 1958, it was decided the building should be demolished. However, before the demolition was completed the building caught fire and burned to the ground.
		</info>
		<info>
			In 1997 the College purchased a private residence that has been renamed St. Ann's in memory of the building that served the Marist Brothers for over 50 years. This former home is part of the 13-acre estate known as Fern Tor, adjacent to Marist College's northern boundary. A previous resident of Fern Tor was Thomas Newbold, one of the founders of the Horticultural Society of New York and an uncle of Pulitzer Prize-winning American novelist and short story writer Edith Wharton.
		</info>
		<images>7</images>
	</building>

	<building name="foy">
		<id>foy</id>
		<name>Foy Townhouses</name>
		<date>1982</date>
		<desc>Sophomore residence</desc>
		<info>
			Foy Townhouses, built in 1982, currently serve as sophomore housing towards the north end of campus.  This 210-student housing complex is divided into seven three-story town houses with space for ten students in each house. The main floor consists of a kitchen, a large common room, and a terrace that overlooks the Hudson River. Upstairs there are three bedrooms and two bathrooms, while the lowest level has a small common room, one bathroom and two bedrooms. Each bedroom is assigned to two students.
		</info>
		
		<info>
			In 2003 these townhouses were named in honor of President Emeritus and Life Trustee, Dr. Linus Richard Foy. He was named President of Marist College in 1958 and, at age 28, became the youngest college president in the United States. Dr. Foy made countless contributions to the development of the College until 1979, when Marist's current President, Dennis J. Murray was appointed.
		</info>
		<images>9</images>
	</building>

	<building name="gartland">
		<id>gartland</id>
		<name>Gartland Commons</name>
		<date>1985</date>
		<desc>Sophomore residence</desc>
		<info>
			Built in 1985, Gartland Commons consist of fifty-two apartments in four separate buildings that house a total of 306 students. Each apartment provides a living room, bathroom, three bedrooms, a fully equipped kitchen, nearby recreational facilities, and a beautiful view overlooking the Hudson River.
		</info>
		<info>
			Gartland Commons are named after John J. Gartland, Jr., a longtime Marist College Benefactor, Board Member, and Advisor. John Gartland served in the U.S. Army Air Force during World War II later earned a bachelor's of science degree from Georgetown University in 1935. After, Gartland earned law degrees from Fordham and St. John's. Marist College awarded Gartland with a doctorate in humane letters in 1980. Gartland served on the boards of numerous local organizations including Marist, the Astor Home, New York Archdiocese Catholic Charities and St. Mary's Church. In addition, Gartland was also honored by the pope as a Knight of the Holy Sepulchre, one of the highest honors the church can bestow on a lay person.
		</info>
		<images>9</images>
	</building>

	<building name="westcedar">
		<id>westcedar</id>
		<name>West Cedar Townhouses</name>
		<date>1998-2000</date>
		<desc>Upperclassman residence</desc>
		<info>
			West Cedar is located across Route 9 on West-Cedar Street and is made up of two sections where upperclassmen can reside: Lower (labeled O-S, completed in 1998) and Upper (labeled T-Y, completed in 2000). Together, these sections contain twelve buildings which can accommodate 468 upperclassmen. Each house features a kitchen, dining area, living room, and two bathrooms. Residents in the complex have access to laundry facilities and campus security.
		</info>
		<images>10</images>
	</building>

	<building name="midrise">
		<id>midrise</id>
		<name>Midrise Hall</name>
		<date></date>
		<desc>Sophomore residence</desc>
		<info></info>
		<images></images>
	</building>

	<building name="library">
		<id>library</id>
		<name>James A. Cannavino Library</name>
		<date>2000</date>
		<desc>Library</desc>
		<info>
			The beautiful stone library overlooking the Hudson River and campus green is named after longtime Trustee and former Chairman of the Board, James A. Cannavino. Developed as part of the worldwide Digital Library Initiative launched by the IBM Corporation to facilitate anytime, anywhere access to books, periodicals, works of art, film, music, and rare manuscripts, the Cannavino Library is a model for academic libraries of the new century. This 83,000-square-foot facility is a state-of-the-art electronic teaching and service center at the hub of an electronic network linking all parts of the Marist campus to libraries and databases throughout the world. In addition to providing a number of spacious study areas and attractive quiet rooms for research, conferences, and collaborative work, the Library also houses the Archives and Special Collections rooms, an office overlooking the campus for the College President, and a multi-media language center on the third floor. A small cafe on the main floor of the Library also provides the students with a gathering place where they can have a bite to eat, drink coffee, and not have to worry quite as much about the level of their voices.
		</info>
		<images>10</images>
	</building>

	<building name="tenney">
		<id>tenney</id>
		<name>Tenney Stadium</name>
		<date></date>
		<desc></desc>
		<info></info>
		<images></images>
	</building>

	<building name="fontainehall">
		<id>fontainehall</id>
		<name>Fontaine Hall</name>
		<date>1956; Rebuilt in 2000</date>
		<desc>Academic building</desc>
		<info>
			The original Fontaine Hall was constructed by the Marist Brothers in 1956 under the supervision of Brother Nilus Donnelly. He supervised Marist Brothers volunteers who worked on building the college during the summer months. Student brothers also worked on the project during the spring and fall semesters, which were lengthened by two weeks to allow small teams to help Brother Nilus year-round. The estimated cost to build the structure was $828,895, but it was built for $350,000 due to the hard work of the Brothers.
		</info>
		<info>
			During a blistering summer day, the brothers were hard at work constructing Fontaine Hall. Two groups of student brothers were applying perma-stone to opposite sides of the building. A hose used to wet the cement was accidentally held so the water arched over the roof, sprinkling the other group of brothers. Declarations of war were issued and both armies met on the roof of Fontaine, buckets of water and hoses at the ready. Twenty minutes later the war was over and both sides returned to work, happy in victory, cool and refreshed.
		</info>
		<info>
			After the building was completed it was named after Brother Paul Ambrose Fontaine, President Emeritus and Life Trustee of Marist College. He played a major role in shaping Marist from a two year junior college to a four year liberal arts college.
		</info>
		<info>
  			As Marist expanded, Fontaine Hall's functions varied to suit the needs of the students.
		</info>
		<info>
			Fontaine Hall was originally attached to the chapel by a passageway. The architecture mirrored that of the chapel, with long laminated beams radiating out from a single pillar to support the wooden roof. An award-winning curtain of glass gave way to a beautiful panoramic view of the Hudson River.
		</info>
		<info>
			The main floor of Fontaine housed a circular study hall with an open space in the center. On the north side was "Our Lady's Library" which held books relating to the Blessed Virgin. It was organized by Brother Cyril Robert, the college librarian and merged with the main collection when the library moved from Donnelly to Fontaine. The northwest corner of the building contained a visitor's suite, dining room, bedroom, and balcony. It was a popular spot to hold group meetings.
		</info>
		<info>
			The lower floor contained a kitchen and dining room which served as the school's cafeteria and provided meals to the faculty and 120 student brothers. A unique crucifix dominated the staircase connecting the study hall to the dining room. Instead of nails going through the palms, the figure of Christ had nails going through His wrists. This scientifically correct approach reflected the Marist Brothers' scholasticism and search for the truth.
		</info>
		<info>
			In 1958, a four-story addition was attached to Fontaine because St. Ann's hermitage was deemed unsafe. The steel frame addition became the new dormitory for the student brothers. In 1974, when the Benoit and Gregory houses were built, the addition was modified to accommodate the offices of the Humanities Department. Later, it housed the Learning Resources Center, which included the library, learning center, and an audiovisual and television facility.
		</info>
		<info>
			Eventually, in 1997, Fontaine Hall had to be demolished to make way for the construction of the James A. Cannavino Library.
		</info>
		<info>
			Fontaine was rebuilt in 2000 as the home of the School of Liberal Arts. It houses multimedia classrooms, a black box theatre, and the Office of College Advancement, including the offices of Alumni Relations and Public Affairs. It also features the Henry Hudson room, a large conference room that offers stunning views of the Hudson River. Up until recently it also contained the MIPO, the Marist College Institute for Public Opinion. The hallway on the first floor, also known as the Gallery Corridor, is lined with photographs of Franklin D. Roosevelt to remind the Marist community of the close affiliation between the College and the FDR Presidential Library in the neighboring town of Hyde Park.
		</info>
		<images>19</images>
	</building>

	<building name="ferntor">
		<id>ferntor</id>
		<name>Fern Tor Arboretum</name>
		<date>1997</date>
		<desc>Arboretum owned by Marist College</desc>
		<info>
			Fern Tor is the 13 acre estate acquired by Marist College in 1997. Located on campus's northern boundary, Fern Tor is a quiet retreat with trees, wildflowers, herbs, shrubs, wildlife, and several ecological habitats. The Hudson River can be viewed from several spots, as it is graced with 800 feet of shoreline. The land Fern Tor is located on remained undeveloped until it was purchased in 1861 by Thomas Newbold for a family home. Newbold constructed a mansion, summerhouse, formal gardens, greenhouses, a man-made pond, and a carriage house. Thomas Newbold's son Frederick nicknames the location Fern Tor after its ferns and rocky hills. The property was later sold to the Way family who then sold the parcel to Marist. The foundations of the mansion are all that remain from the previous owners. Fern Tor is currently used by both environmental majors and non-science majors as an ecological lab or to just enjoy the peace and quiet.
		</info>
		<images>29</images>
	</building>

	<building name="hancock">
		<id>hancock</id>
		<name>Hancock Center</name>
		<date>2011</date>
		<desc>Academic building</desc>
		<info>
			The Hancock Center is named after the lead donor and vice chair of the Marist Board of Trustees, Ellen Hancock, and her husband Jason. The 57,000 square foot academic center opened in 2011 and houses the School of Computer Science and Mathematics, faculty offices, nine classrooms, six conference/seminar rooms, and three computer labs. In addition, the Marist College Institute for Public Opinion (MIPO), the International Programs Office, and a small cafe is also located in the Hancock Center. The $35 million Center includes the Center for Collaborative and On-Demand Computing, the Institute for Data Center Professionals, and the IBM-Marist Joint Study Program which features some of the most advanced technology available. The Hancock Center's look was inspired by the original buildings acquired with the Bech Estate: The Greystone, Kieran Gatehouse, and St. Peter's cottage. Designed by Robert A. M. Stern Architects, LLP, the Center also reduces environmental impact with energy efficient lighting and a green roof that absorbs and filters rain water.
		</info>
		<images>25</images>
	</building>

	<building name="musicbuilding">
		<id>musicbuilding</id>
		<name>Music Building</name>
		<date>2013</date>
		<desc>Academic building</desc>
		<info></info>
		<images></images>
	</building>

	<building name="woodcliff">
		<id>woodcliff</id>
		<name>Woodcliff Pleasure Park</name>
		<date>1927</date>
		<desc>Former amusement park</desc>
		<info>
			The Woodcliff Pleasure Park, open from 1927 to 1941, was a well-known amusement park along the Hudson River. It was located where Gartland Apartments and the Gartland Atheltic Field stand today.
		</info>
		<info>
			The riverfront property has passed through many hands, starting with Jack Flack Winslow. Mr. Winslow owned, alongside Erastus Corning, the Rensselaer Iron Works and Albany Iron Works - the most prominent iron works in the nation. He and his second wife, Harriet Wickes, moved to the Wood Cliff estate in 1868. There was one main house along with three summer houses called Crag, Cliff, and Lookout. Winding paths, foot bridges, a farm, a greenhouse, and a small stream created a serene setting that was renowned throughout the banks of the Hudson. After Winslow and Harriett passed away, the estate was sold to John B. Marian and his wife, Elizabeth. The Marians planned to uphold the beloved estate, but sold Wood Cliff to Fred Ponty who turned the property into an amusement park, or pleasure park as they were known at the time.
		</info>
		<info>
			Ponty received the property with all the existing structures on April 18, 1927. It was ideal space due to the closeness of the Hudson River which provided access to day liners from New York City. Day liners could transport as many as 18,000 day trippers in addition to a trolley service that transported local Poughkeepsie citizens to the park. It is believed the park opened on a limited basis in 1927 and gained full operation the following year.
		</info>
		<info>
			Woodcliff Pleasure Park was completed in one year. Costing over $1,000,000, it covered 27 acres and featured a variety of attractions able to please any thrill-seeker. The mansion was converted into an inn with a restaurant, dance hall, and a bar. The gatehouses were transformed into entrance point. The stables and stableman's house were torn down and a notable pink ticket house was added. The park developed many feature entertainment venues. This included bumper cars, pony rides, carousels, a tunnel of love, Ferris wheels, arcades, a giant airplane swing, midway games, shoot-the-chutes, shooting, galleries, whips, lake boat rides, and a low coaster called The Caterpillar. Other entertainment attractions incorporated wrestling, boxing matches, a roller skating rink, a Tom Thumb golf course, equestrian events, baseball games, and an occasional fireworks show. Visitors could walk around in gardens (which were illuminated at night) and have picnic lunches. Special talents and acts also visited the park, the most notable being The Ringling Brothers Barnum and Bailey Circus.
		</info>
		<info>
			Despite all the quality entertainment, the main attractions were the pool and The Blue Streak roller coaster. The Blue Streak was built by Joseph McKee. He followed the designs created by engineer Vernon Keenan, who built the famous Cyclone of Coney Island. The two roller coasters were very similar in that they were both "out and back" coaster (the end was also the start), both constructed with wood, and chain pulled.
		</info>
		<info>
			The Blue Streak is estimated at 120 feet to 140 feet high and 2,000 to 3,200 feet in length. At the time, it was the highest roller coaster in the world and remained so until the "coaster wars" of the 1970's. The Blue Streak also held the speed record for 54 years, at 65.2 miles per hour until 1981. These records made Blue Streak a legend in amusement park history.
		</info>
		<info>
			The pool at Woodcliff Pleasure Park cost around $90,000 and was able to hold 3,000 swimmers, with the estimated pool measurements being around 50 by 200 feet. The park's pool may have been an extension of an original pool constructed by the Winslow's around 1918. The pool had a modern filtration system, which was highly bragged about, and bathhouses were added in 1930. The Woodcliff Pleasure Park Pool was noted as one of the largest pools on the East Coast, and probably one of the biggest in the country.
		</info>
		<info>
			Unfortunately, the success at Woodcliff Pleasure Park was short-lived.  At the turn of the decade the Stock Market Crash heavily influenced the steady decline of Woodcliff Pleasure Park, along with many other amusement parks. Although the Hudson River Day Line brought thousands of visitors, certain events tarnished the park's reputation. In July of 1914, a group of African Americans were denied right to swim in the pool. Outraged, they retaliated by throwing rocks around the pool. Later that summer 3,000 day liners arrived and when the visitors were denied beer, they smashed windows, mirrors, destroyed furniture, and threw rocks and bottles which resulted in injuring a child. Knives, and even a hatchet, were involved. The New York State Police were called to control this riot, but could not help. The damage extended to four automobiles and several buildings. The park closed in August 1941, a few weeks after Fred Ponty died.
		</info>
		<info>
			The rides were dismantled after the park closed. The historic Blue Streak's steel parts were given to the WWII war effort and the wood was used by the Marist Brothers to build a beehive. Only the picnic area, gatehouses, main house, barn, outhouse, and pool were left. Many different groups, such as the City of Poughkeepsie and the Polish American Club, fought over ownership of the park. Eventually a construction company used the area to store heavy equipment. By this time only the building with the billiards room remained.
		</info>
		<info>
			Marist College bought the property around 1983. The College built student apartments on the land and later created an athletic field. To put the park in perspective of today, the Blue Streak stood on the softball diamond, the pool on the soccer field, and the pink ticket house east of the Blue Streak on Route 9.
		</info>
		<images></images>
	</building>

	<building name="benoitgregory">
		<id>benoitgregory</id>
		<name>Benoit and Gregory Houses</name>
		<date>1968</date>
		<desc>Former Marist Brothers residence</desc>
		<info>
			Benoit &amp; Gregory Houses were built in 1968 as residences for the Marist Brothers living on campus. Both had sixteen bedrooms, was octagonal, and constructed identically. Benoit House was named in the memory of Brother Francis Xavier Benoit who served Marist as a teacher for nineteen years in addition to serving as a Director of Construction. Gregory House was named in remembrance of Brother Joseph Gregory Marchessault who was chairman of the Physics Department at Marist until his death in 1969. Benoit &amp; Gregory were both removed in 2009, being replaced with the Hancock Center.
		</info>
		<images>1</images>
	</building>

	<building name="leonidoff">
		<id>leonidoff</id>
		<name>Leonidoff Field</name>
		<date>1965</date>
		<desc>Athletic field</desc>
		<info>
			Leonidoff Field is Marist's first major athletic field, providing a venue for sports and intermural activities hosted by the Marist Athletics Department. It is also home to Tenney Stadium, which offers seating for over 5,000 spectators.
		</info>
		<info>
			The field was dedicated to Dr. Aleski A. Leonidoff in 1968. Leonidoff was born and raised in Russia, and developed a relationship with Marist through Jack Gartland. During his tenure as a physician at St. Francis Hospital, he donated money to the College for the construction of the field. In addition, he donated funds to support a scholarship for students specializing in science and pre-medical studies.
		</info>
		<info>
			Since its beginnings in 1965, multiple improvements have been made to the field. An irrigation system consisting of 11 zones and 36 sprinkler heads was installed to keep the then-Kentucky bluegrass, fescue, and rye natural turf looking its best. In 2001 Musco field lighting was installed to allow night games to occur, opening up a new range of possibilities for the field.
		</info>
		<info>
			Marist Football has since been the program that has seen the most activity on the field, but other teams use it regularly, such as soccer, lacrosse, and intermural sports.
		</info>
		<images>10</images>
	</building>

	<building name="martin">
		<id>martin</id>
		<name>Martin Boathouse</name>
		<date>1963</date>
		<desc>Marist College's boathouse</desc>
		<info>
			The Martin Boathouse, also known as the Marist Boathouse, was built in 1963 to house the rowing and sailing equipment of Marist College. It is named in memory of William Martin, who was the chairman responsible for funding the construction of the boathouse. There are two ramps that lead directly into the Hudson River, allowing the crew team quick and easy access for training and competitions, such as races and regattas. At first, Blue Jays, 13-foot wooden sloop rigged boats, were used by students and faculty for competition and pleasure sailing. Later, in 1966, these were replaced by Barnegats, 19-foot fiberglass sloops. These sloops could hold six people, but were used in competitions with a crew of two.  They were later replaced with smaller boats.
		</info>
		<info>
			Before Marist built the Martin boathouse, the city of Poughkeepsie owned the other boathouses on the waterfront property: the California Boathouse and Cornell Boathouse. These were used for local high school crew teams in the National Crew Regattas. Marist was allowed to buy the two boathouses and develop the waterfront property under the condition that the local high school teams would still be able to use them for their crew activities.
		</info>
		<info>
			Marist faculty believed a Butler type construction for the boathouse would be the most beneficial. It would be utilized for the storage of shells, and also serve as a dormitory for visiting crews. Once the season was over, the space could be used as an athletic facility for gymnastics, weight training lifting, and as a training space for the crew team members. The goal of this plan was to make team practices easier and more convenient and to offer greater hospitality to visiting teams.
		</info>
		<info>
			The upper floor of the boathouse, consisting of two rooms, is furnished with restroom and shower facilities as well as a sleeping space for visiting teams who compete in regattas on the Hudson River. Larry Davis, a past Marist crew coach, used to live in the boathouse with his wife, Vicki. They moved to the boathouse in August of 1981 when Larry was hired to be the business manager of athletics at the McCann Center and coach of the varsity crew team. Vicki, quickly adapting to the unique space, made some small home improvements and furnished the floor by adding wallpaper to make it homier.
		</info>
		<info>
			The Marist crew team won the prestigious Haight Trophy for five consecutive years, but their streak ended in 1966. The team's crowning achievement came in 2002 when they qualified for the Henley Cup Regatta in Oxford, England. Unfortunately, they did not make it past the second round, as they were defeated by Harvard, who was the overall winner.
		</info>
		<info>
			The boathouse is named after William Martin, a local insurance agent who was the chairman of the fund drive to construct the boathouse. He passed away before the boathouse's completion and Brother Joannes requested it be named in his memory.
		</info>
		<images>8</images>
	</building>

	<building name="cornell">
		<id>cornell</id>
		<name>Cornell Boathouse</name>
		<date>1977</date>
		<desc>Marist College's boathouse</desc>
		<info>
			In 1894 representatives from Columbia University, Cornell University, and the University of Pennsylvania selected the Hudson River at Poughkeepsie as the site for regattas of their newly formed Intercollegiate Rowing Association (IRA). The first Poughkeepsie Regatta was held in June of 1895 and attracted more than 30,000 spectators. The challenging four-mile course ran south from Crum Elbow (near Hyde Park) to just south of the current site of the Mid-Hudson Bridge.
		</info>
		<info>
			Poughkeepsie soon became known as the "Rowing Capital of the World," hosting IRA regattas from 1895-1949. In addition to the founding members, participants over the years included California, Georgetown, Harvard, MIT, Navy, Princeton, Rutgers, Stanford, Syracuse, Washington, Wisconsin and Yale. In 1949, the IRA moved its annual regatta briefly to Ohio, and then to Onondaga Lake near Syracuse.
		</info>
		<info>
			Marist acquired the historic Cornell boathouse from the university of which it is named in 1977, as part a deal with the City of Poughkeepsie. This would enable local high school rowing programs to have access to the facility. This stipulation remained in effect until 2002. A five-year restoration began in 2004. The process began with the addition of windows and replacing outer shingles. During the process, workers tore down inner walls, installed insulation, replaced the deck, repainted the ceiling beams, and added an elevator.
		</info>
		<info>
			When completed in 2009, Marist's historic Cornell Boathouse stands two-stories tall and remains as a functional boathouse on the first floor, while the second level plays host to a wide variety of campus events. The boathouse has a number of original features despite the remodeling. There is a plaque commemorating the dedication of the structure that hangs above a refurbished gas fireplace. Also, the second floor is decorated with wooden beams overhead, which provided the original structure to the boathouse in the 19th century.
		</info>
		<images></images>
	</building>
</campus>
