<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<timeline>
	<milestone name="1904 (Bech Estate)">
		<id>1904</id>
		<name>Highlights on 1904 (Bech Estate)</name>
		<feature>
			<li>1858: Greystone was built as a two-story barn</li>
			<li>1870: (Kieran) Gatehouse &amp; gardener's cottage (St. Peter's) built on Bech property</li>
			<li>1894: The Cornell Boathouse was built</li>
			<li>1895: The first Poughkeepsie Regatta was held</li>
			<li>December 22, 1904: The Marist Brothers receive their certificate of incorporation</li>
		</feature>
	</milestone>

	<milestone name="1905 - 1929 (Novitiate)">
		<id>1905</id>
		<name>Highlights on 1905 - 1929 (Novitiate)</name>
		<feature>
			<li>1905: The Marist Brothers purchase property and a house from Thomas McPherson along the eastern shore of the Hudson River in Poughkeepsie, NY. The Brothers name the building and property St. Ann's Hermitage.</li>
			<li>1906: The Marist Brothers begin farming and gardening - cows, pigs, chickens, pigeons, rabbits, and even bees will all eventually be reared on campus. The Brothers will trade some of their produce with nurses from St. Francis Hospital after its incorporation in December 17, 1913 in exchange for medical care.</li>
			<li>February 21,1906: The first students on campus arrive; 12 Juniors from St. Hyacinthe, Canada</li>
			<li>July 26, 1908: Feast of St. Anne; Nine postulants take the Marist Habit, becoming the first student brothers on campus </li>
			<li>August 27, 1908: The Brothers purchase the Edward Bech estate to enable the Hermitage to expand and obtain Greystone, St. Peter's, and the Gate House</li>
			<li>November 1910: Brother M. Florentius is named director and Professor, thus unofficially becoming the first "Academic Dean" on campus</li>
			<li>1911: The Juniorate is affiliated with St. Ann's Academy with permission of the Regents in Albany allowing juniors to take Regents Exams</li>
			<li>December 17, 1913: St. Francis Hospital is incorporated</li>
			<li>1915: The Juniorate grotto is begun northeast of St. Ann's Hermitage</li>
			<li>November 1916: The Juniorate, previously the MacPherson mansion, becomes the first building to have electricity</li>
			<li>January 2, 1917: Centenary of the Founding of the Marist Brothers</li>
			<li>January 1922: Brother Leo becomes Provincial, replacing Brother Heribert</li>
			<li>1924: The Novitiate grotto of Our Lady of Sorrows and adjoining recess of Our Lord in agony are built</li>
			<li>1925: The NYS Board of Regents permanently accredited our high school as a Senior High School</li>
			<li>1927: Woodcliff Pleasure Park is built at the current site of Gartland Commons</li>
			<li>1928: Major renovations are started to Greystone to add a library, laboratories, a third floor for dorm space, and the steam laundry in the basement is moved to Marian</li>
			<li>1928: Marist training school is opened under Fordham auspices</li>
			<li>1929: First college level courses are offered through Fordham University</li>
			<li>1929: The carriage house is officially named Greystone</li>
		</feature>
	</milestone>

	<milestone name="1930 - 1945 (Marist Training School)">
		<id>1930</id>
		<name>Highlights on 1930 - 1945 (Marist Training School)</name>
		<feature>
			<li>April 9, 1930: Marist Training School is permanently accredited by the Regents in Albany as an independent 2-year college</li>
			<li>1937: A printing shop is started on campus in the basement of St. Peter's</li>
			<li>June 19, 1939: The Juniorate lake is transformed into a swimming pool and opens for swimming, complete with a diving board</li>
			<li>1941: Woodcliff Pleasure Park is demolished</li>
			<li>September 1941: The cement floor of St. Mary's dormitory is poured</li>
			<li>March 1942: Public phone system installed</li>
		</feature>
	</milestone>

	<milestone name="1946 - 1957 (Marian College)">
		<id>1946</id>
		<name>Highlights on 1946 - 1957 (Marian College)</name>
		<feature>
			<li>1946: New York grants official four-year charter status and the Marian College seal is adopted. It is on this seal where the school's motto "Orare et Laborare" - Latin for "To Pray and to Work" - first appears, and can still be seen on the current Marist College Seal</li>
			<li>1947: Marist celebrates its first graduating class of four student Brothers</li>
			<li>1947: Marian Hall is built as a gym; The first large building on campus</li>
			<li>1953: Lady Seat of Wisdom Chapel is built by Marist faculty and Marist Brothers</li>
			<li>1956: The old Fontaine Hall is built by the Marist Brothers behind the chapel to serve as a residence and study hall</li>
			<li>1957: Adrian Hall is built by the Marist Brothers to serve as a student lounge</li>
		</feature>
	</milestone>

	<milestone name="1958 - 1969 (Marist College)">
		<id>1958</id>
		<name>Highlights on 1958 - 1969 (Marist College)</name>
		<feature>
			<li>October 23, 1958: St. Ann's Hermitage is "accidentally" burned down</li>
			<li>November 28 1958: Dr. Linus Richard Foy becomes youngest college president at age 28</li>
			<li>1958: The original Fontaine Hall catches fire prior to demolition completion</li>
			<li>1960: Official title of Marist College is given, and lay males are allowed admission to pursue undergraduate studies and, upon the request of IBM, the college establishes an evening division for their workers</li>
			<li>1960: The Bryne house is built</li>
			<li>1961: Marist celebrates its first graduating class of non-brothers</li>
			<li>1962: Sheahan Hall, The first residential dorm not built by Marist Brothers, is constructed and becomes the first to house women</li>
			<li>1962: Donnelly Hall is built by the Marist Brothers</li>
			<li>1963: The Bech homestead is demolished</li>
			<li>1963: Byrne Residence, the William H. Martin Boathouse, and Leo Hall are built</li>
			<li>1965: The Marist College Football Team is introduced as a club</li>
			<li>1965: The first issue of The Circle is published</li>
			<li>1965: The tallest building on campus, Champagnat Hall, as well as the Student Center is completed</li>
			<li>1965: Marist establishes the Upward Bound program, currently one of the longest established in the country</li>
			<li>1966: Women are officially admitted to the evening division</li>
			<li>1967: The first mainframe computer is installed in Adrian Hall</li>
			<li>1968: Women enter the day division, making the college coeducational</li>
			<li>1968: The Benoit House and Gregory House are built</li>
			<li>October 19, 1968: Dr. Aleksei A. Leonidoff provides the first substantial financial gift to Marist College from a lay person. He donated $25,000 to develop a football and soccer field, named Leonidoff Field in dedication of the benefactor</li>
			<li>1969: Marist College sheds Catholic ties as ownership of the college is transferred to the Marist College Educational Corporation</li>
			<li>1969: Women are invited to live on campus</li>
		</feature>
	</milestone>

	<milestone name="1970 - 1979 (Marist College)">
		<id>1970</id>
		<name>Highlights on 1970 - 1979 (Marist College)</name>
		<feature>
			<li>1970: The Poughkeepsie cemetery is covered over to build the McCann Recreational Center</li>
			<li>1973: Marist begins a cooperative program with secondary schools in the area allowing selected high school seniors to take first-year college courses and "bridge" into college</li>
			<li>1976: The Kirk House is built</li>
			<li>April 17, 1977: McCann Recreation Center opens including the Fieldhouse and Natatorium, one of the premier aquatic facilities in the Metro Atlantic Athletic Conference</li>
			<li>1978: The Marist Institute for Public Opinion (MIPO) is established by Dr. Lee Miringoff</li>
			<li>1978: The Marist College Football Team is moved from club to NCAA Division III status</li>
			<li>1979: Dr. Dennis J. Murray becomes the second president of Marist College</li>
		</feature>
	</milestone>

	<milestone name="1980 - 1993 (Marist College)">
		<id>1980</id>
		<name>Highlights on 1980 - 1993 (Marist College)</name>
		<feature>
			<li>1980: The former Woodcliff Amusement Park property is acquired to build Gartland Commons</li>
			<li>1980: The print shop closes, replaced by the copy room in Donnelly</li>
			<li>1981: Marist Men's Soccer completes their first season and Division I basketball is introduced to the McCann Center</li>
			<li>1982: The first set of townhouses for upper-class students are built and named in honor of President Foy in 2003</li>
			<li>1983: The old gym, Marian Hall is transformed into a dormitory</li>
			<li>1984: Marist Volleyball celebrates their first season</li>
			<li>1984: Marist receives $2.5 million in equipment, and almost $2 million in software from IBM to expand academic and administrative uses of computers on campus</li>
			<li>1985: The Gartland Commons apartment complex is built, Named after John J. Gartland, Jr.</li><li>1986: Marist hosts the First Silver Needle Fashion Show</li>
			<li>1986: The Marist Band is created consisting of  just two trumpet players and a bandleader</li>
			<li>1987: The Lowell Thomas Communications Center opens, housing the Dean of Faculty, the Media Center, the School of Communication and the Arts, and the School of Global and Professional Programs</li>
			<li>1988: The Marist/IBM Joint Study begins with the installation of a $10 million IBM 3090 mainframe computer in Donnelly Hall, placing Marist among the most technologically advanced liberal arts colleges in the country. Renovations to Donnelly begin to provide classrooms, lecture halls, the Fashion Program, a science center, information technology facilities, a computer lab and administrative offices</li>
			<li>1990: The Margaret M. and Charles H. Dyson Center is completed providing a home for the School of Management, the School of Social and Behavioral Sciences, and the School of Global and Professional Programs and Graduate &amp; Adult Enrollment</li>
			<li>October 1990: The Gatehouse is dedicated and renamed the Kieran Gatehouse</li>
			<li>March 26, 1992: Marist Softball celebrates the christening of their new field located at Gartland Athletic Field</li>
			<li>1992: The men's lacrosse team plays its first full Division I season</li>
			<li>1993: The New Townhouses are built</li>
			<li>1993: The Marist Football Team begins to play at the NCAA Division I-AA level</li>
		</feature>
	</milestone>

	<milestone name="1994 - 1999 (Marist College)">
		<id>1994</id>
		<name>Highlights on 1994 - 1999 (Marist College)</name>
		<feature>
			<li>1989: A glass-enclosed entry is constructed which connects the Student Center to Champagnat Hall</li>
			<li>1991: The McCann Baseball Field is built, bringing Division I baseball to the Mid-Hudson Valley</li>
			<li>Summer 1994: Renovations and expansions are made to the student center providing a bookstore, new dining facilities, a Cabaret, and the Admissions office symbolized by the dramatic rotunda, as well as the building of Mid-Rise Residence Hall</li>
			<li>1995: The campus theater located in the Student Center is renovated and renamed the Nelly Goletti Theater</li>
			<li>1995: Women's soccer is introduced as the fourth intercollegiate program</li>
			<li>1996: Talmadge Court Apartments are purchased</li>
			<li>1997: The Steel Plant Studio is purchased to temporarily house the library</li>
			<li>1997: Fern Tor estate is acquired</li>
			<li>1997: An addition of the 4,200-square-foot Coaches Complex is added to the McCann Recreation Center as well as a 20,000-square-foot expansion to provide the College community and student-athletes access to a top-flight training and conditioning facility</li>
			<li>1997: Marist College purchases a private residence and names it St. Ann's, in memory</li>	
			<li>1997: Women lacrosse joins as an intercollegiate program</li>
			<li>1998: Lower West Townhouses are completed</li>
			<li>1998: Marist launches New York State's First AACSB-accredited online MBA program</li>
		</feature>
	</milestone>

	<milestone name="2000 - 2009 (Marist College)">
		<id>2000</id>
		<name>Highlights on 2000 - 2009 (Marist College)</name>
		<feature>
			<li>2000: The natatorium becomes the home of the women's water polo team</li>
			<li>2000: Upper West Townhouses are completed</li>
			<li>2000: The 83,000 square-foot, state-of-the-art James A. Cannavino Library is dedicated. The library houses the College's archival collections and a multimedia presentation room, and hosts several student academic services offices, including the Center for Career Services, the Higher Education Opportunity Program (HEOP), the Office of International Education, and the Writing Center. It has more ports-per-student than any other academic library in the country</li>
			<li>May 2000: The new Fontaine Hall is opened, housing multimedia classrooms, a black box theatre, a conference room, the School of Liberal Arts, the Office of College Advancement, and the offices of Alumni Relations and Public Affairs</li>
			<li>May 6, 2000: The Adrian Building is removed to provide space for construction of the James A. Cannavino Library</li>
			<li>Summer 2000: The Dr. Maynard Center for Sports Medicine in the McCann Center is turned into a top-flight athletic training room, and the Academic Enhancement Center for Student-Athletes is redesigned into a premier academic facility </li>
			<li>2004: A five-year restoration on the Historic Cornell Boathouse begins</li>
			<li>2005: The Fulton Street Townhouses are constructed</li>
			<li>2006: Marist College's branch campus opens in Florence, Italy with the Lorenzo De' Medici School</li>
			<li>Fall 2006: The Tennis Pavilion is built providing the first on-campus home to our men's and women's tennis program. This pavilion is one of three total tennis venues in the area that qualifies as a host site of the U.S. Open</li>
			<li>2007: Longview Park is completed with a bike/walk path along the Hudson River's east shore, a fishing pier, the renovation of Marist's historic Cornell boathouse, and better access to scenic vistas, particularly from the gazebo built on a promontory in the center of the park</li>
			<li>2007: Marist accepts only 41 percent of applicants, making this the lowest acceptance rate in the college's history</li>
			<li>2007: Marist receives the largest government grant to date, a $5 million capital grant from New York State to build a technology center within the Hancock Building</li>
			<li>March 2007: The Women's Basketball Team makes it to the sweet sixteen in the NCAA Tournament</li>
			<li>April 2007: Kiplingers Personal Finance magazine Marist is named one of the 50 "best buys" in private college education, the only New York State college on the list</li>
			<li>October 2007: Tenney Stadium is opened, featuring a new grandstand, increasing the capacity to 5,000 spectators, a concession stand, rest rooms, team rooms, state-of-the-art field turf, a new scoreboard, and amphitheater-style seating on the west side</li>
			<li>2008: Marist begins a $3 million dollar renovation to Donnelly Hall</li>
			<li>Spring 2008: Marist celebrates the kickoff of its first comprehensive capital campaign, The Campaign for Marist</li>
			<li>2009: Benoit and Gregory Houses are removed, providing the future site of the Hancock Center</li>
			<li>2009: Restorations to Marist's historic Cornell Boathouse is completed, remaining as a functional boathouse on the first floor, and a banquet hall on the second</li>
			<li>2009: The Raymond A. Rich Leadership Institute (Payne Mansion) is granted to Marist College</li>
			<li>2009: The Marist Football team joins the Pioneer Football League as its 10th member</li>
		</feature>
	</milestone>

	<milestone name="2010 - 2012 (Marist College)">
		<id>2010</id>
		<name>Highlights on 2010 - 2012 (Marist College)</name>
		<feature>
			<li>January 2011: Construction begins on the 11,660 square-foot addition to the James J. McCann Center, providing the men's and women's basketball programs with locker rooms, lounges, a film theater, video editing room, and a conference room</li>
			<li>May 5, 2011: The Marist Fashion Program celebrates it's 25th annual Silver Needle Fashion Show</li>
			<li>May 6, 2011: The Hancock Center academic building is dedicated, providing students and faculty with the most advanced information technology. It houses the School of Computer Science and Mathematics, as well as a state-of-the-art student investment center, the Marist-IBM Joint Study, the Institute for Data Center Professionals, and The Marist Institute of Public Opinion</li>
			<li>July 2011: The Route 9 Underpass Pedestrian Walkway is built allowing students to safely get to the other side of route 9 without interfering with traffic</li>
			<li>September 2011: Construction to the McCann Center Fieldhouse begins with an 11,660 square-foot addition to provide new locker rooms for our basketball program as well as renovations to seating to create a "bowl-effect", more lobby space, and convenient bathrooms</li>
			<li>2012: The IBM SmartCloud solution project is established at Marist College</li>
			<li>Summer 2012: Renovations to the Lowell Thomas Communications Center begins</li>
		</feature>
	</milestone>
</timeline>
